Guide to the Judy Woodruff papers, 1980-2009 and undated RL.11852
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Judy Woodruff papers
1980-2009 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11852
148.5 Linear Feet
Judy Woodruff is a broadcast journalist covering U.S. politics whose career has spanned work at NBC, CNN, and PBS. This collection documents her professional life, consisting of extensive research and subject files, correspondence including viewer mail, speaking appearances and engagements, and service including the Duke University Board of Trustees and the Interntional Women's Media Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are still in original housing which may be sealed with tape. Staff will need to open box to facilitate researcher access.
Provenance
The Judy Woodruff papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2014.
Arrangement
Materials remain in the order in which they were received, and the series were derived from the donor's groupings. The collection guide is divided into series which are then sorted chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Judy Woodruff (b. 1946) is a broadcast journalist who has covered politics and other news for networks including NBC, CNN, and PBS over a career that began in the early 1970s. After graduating from Duke University, Woodruff began working at a local Atlanta ABC affiliate. Her national profile rose when she covered Jimmy Carter's 1976 election, which took her to NBC, where she became a political correspondent. Her long association with PBS began in 1983, when she became the chief Washington correspondent for the MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour. From 1993-2005, Woodruff worked with CNN, where she anchored the show Inside Politics. She has also taught courses at both Harvard and Duke. Since 2011, she has anchored news shows including the PBS NewsHour and made Frontline documentaries for PBS. She has served on the Board of Trustees of Duke University and the Duke Endowment, and is a co-founder of the International Women's Media Foundation.
Collection Overview
The collection includes files documenting Woodruff's journalism career with CBS, NBC, the MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour, CNN and other news outlets as well as her service at Duke on the Board of Trustees, and the board of the International Women's Media Foundation. Files range from extensive research and subject files to project files, viewer correspondence, interview material, writings, speeches, and audio/visual materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials must be reformatted before use.
Press and politics -- United States; Women in television broadcasting -- United States; Women in the broadcasting industry -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Woodruff, Judy; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; MacNeil/Lehrer Productions.; PBS newshour; Frontline (Television program); International Women's Media Foundation; Duke Endowment; Duke University. Board of Trustees
- Research Files, 1980-2009 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  Contains materials used by Woodruff in the production of her work. Includes research files, subject files, notebooks, blue cards, and personal notes. Topics include PBS research, MacNeil Lehrer research, Interviews, Politics, and the Middle East.
  - Frontline Files (Box 11, Box 46, Box 47)
  - PBS Research, undated (Box 51)
  - Reporting Notes; Departure From CNN (Box 6)
  - Research and Story Files, undated (Box 10)
  - Research Files, undated (Box 44, Box 52, Box 57)
  - Research Files, Notebooks, Blue Cards, undated (Box 38)
  - Research, Interviews, MacNeil Lehrer, undated (Box 4)
  - Women and Roe v. Wade (Box 63)
  - Research Files, 1980-1984 (Box 13)
  - Research Files, Personal Notes, 1980-1989 (Box 77)
  - Research Files, 1982-1986 (Box 54)
  - Research Files, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Box 17, Box 19)
  - Research Files, 1984 (Box 41, Box 50)
  - Research Files Asia/Middle East, 1984-1990 (Box 39)
  - Research Files, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Research Files, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Research Files, 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - MacNeil Lehrer Files; PBS; CNN, 1987-1994 (Box 68)
  - Subject Files, 1988-1996 (Box 40)
  - Research Files, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
  - Research Files, 1989-1992 (Box 37)
  - Research Files, 1990-1992 (Box 49)
  - Research Files, 1990-1993 (Box 56)
  - Research Files, 1990-1999 (Box 89)
  - Research Files, 1990-2009 (Box 43)
  - Election, 1992 (Box 71)
  - Research Files, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Research Files, 1993-1994 (Box 55, Box 58)
  - CNN Presents, 1994-1996 (Box 97)
  - CNN Programming, 1993-2004 (Box 42)
  - Research Files Politics, 1994-1996 (Box 29, Box 33)
  - UN World Conference on Women, Bejing, Women Research, 1995 (Box 81)
  - Research Files, 1995-1996 (Box 23, Box 26)
  - Research Files, 1995-1999 (Box 88)
  - Election Files, 1996 (Box 64, Box 67)
  - Convention Political Guide, Democratic Convention Chicago, Logistics, Clippings, CNN Guide to Coverage, ABA Commission on Women Panel, 1996 (Box 61)
  - Research Files, 1996-2000 (Box 78)
  - Research Notes, 1997-1999 (Box 36)
  - Research Files, 1998-2000 (Box 80)
  - Subject Files, 1998-2001 (Box 45)
  - Research Files, 1999-2000 (Box 76)
  - Election Files, 2000 (Box 99)
  - Subject Files, 2000-2005 (Box 25)
  - Inside Politics, 2001 (Box 73)
  - Research Files, 2001 (Box 32)
  - Research Files, Notebooks, 2001-2004 (Box 18)
- Correspondence, 1982-2001 and undated
  These materials consist of Woodruff's professional correspondence and a substantial amount of viewer mail.
  - Viewer Mail, undated (Box 44)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 46)
  - Viewer Mail, 1982-1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 83)
  - Viewer Mail and Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Viewer Mail and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 50)
  - Viewer Mail, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Viewer Mail, 1988-1998 (Box 38)
  - Viewer Mail, 1992-1994 (Box 91)
  - Viewer Mail and Personal Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 87)
  - Viewer Mail and Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 96)
  - Correspondence, 1995-2005 (Box 42)
  - Viewer Mail, 1996 (Box 74)
  - Viewer Mail, 1996 (Box 100)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 83)
  - Viewer Mail, 2000-2001 (Box 28)
- Engagements and Service, 1980-2009 and undated
  This grouping contains materials documenting Woodruff's appearances at events, including her speeches. It also includes materials documenting her service on various boards, including the Duke University Board of Trustees and the Duke Endowment.
  - Engagements, undated (Box 11, Box 46)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1980-2009 (Box 70)
  - Engagements Completed, 1989-1991 (Box 5)
  - Speeches, 1990-1995 (Box 65)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1993 (Box 72)
  - Engagements, 1994 (Box 92)
  - Events, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Events, 1996 (Box 69)
  - Engagements, 1996-2002 (Box 15)
  - Engagements, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Engagements, 1998 (Box 95)
  - Engagements, 1999-2000 (Box 93)
  - Engagements, 2001-2002 (Box 21)
  - Engagements, 2002-2003 (Box 53)
  - Engagements, 2003 (Box 58)
  - Engagements, 2003-2004 (Box 20)
  - Board Service, 1980-2009 (Box 70)
  - Board Meetings, Executive Committee, East European Congress, 1991 (Box 66)
  - Duke University (Box 51)
  - Duke University, 1993-1996 (Box 21)
  - Duke University, 2003-2004 (Box 23)
  - Spina Bifida (Box 27, Box 30)
  - International Women's Media Foundation, undated (Box 57)
  - International Women's Media Foundation, 1986-1998 (Box 90)
  - International Women's Media Foundation, 1990-1998 (Box 84)
  - International Women's Media Foundation, 1990-2003 (Box 60)
  - International Women's Media Foundation Africa Trip, 1993 (Box 62)
  - International Women's Media Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 66)
  - International Women's Media Foundation, 1995-2000 (Box 79)
- Career Documentation, Ephemera, A/V, 1986-2004 and undated
  These materials chiefly document Woodruff's career, including press coverage, awards, and biographies. Also includes contact lists, calendars, ephemera, printed materials, organizational files, and a photo album from the 1995 Beijing Women's Conference.
  - Buttons (Box 56)
  - Contact Lists, Notebooks, Day Planners, Ephemera (Box 8)
  - Judy Woodruff Press (Box 12, Box 48, Box 55)
  - Early Career, 1986-1993 (Box 47)
  - UN/NGO/Beijing Trip with Photo Album, 1995 (Box 82)
  - Organizations (A-C); Freedom Forum, 2001-2003 (Box 30)
  - Organizations (N-P) (Box 42)
  - Print Publications, 1996-2000 (Box 80)
  - Awards and Bios, 2001-2004 (Box 18)
  - VHS Tapes: IP airchecks, War in Iraq, Etc. (Box 85-86)
  - VHS, Betacam: CNN, 1990s (Box 94)
  - Beta/VHS Footage (Box 98)
  - Videos: Bernie w/Senator Byrd, Rep. Gephardt, Jay Leno, Mack McLarty, Begleita, Tom Foley, Bob Dole, Ross Perot, Bill Clinton, Downsizing the Dream, Us and Them (Box 34)
  - Betamax, VHS: Appearances (Box 75)